Alfred H. Barr, Jr. Papers
The Museum of Modern Art, Publisher
Alfred H. Barr, Jr. Papers
1927-1984
The Museum of Modern Art, Museum Archives 11 West 53 Street New York, NY 10019-5497 moma.org/learn/resources/archives
Alfred H. Barr, Jr.
83.5 linear feet
Provenance
Barr, Alfred Hamilton, 1902-1981.; Barr, Alfred Hamilton, 1902-1981 -- Archives.; Picasso, Pablo, 1881-1973 -- Archives.; Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.) -- History -- Sources.; Foundation for the Arts, Religion, and Culture -- History -- Sources.; Art, Abstract.; Art, Russian.; Art, Modern -- 20th century.; Art -- Exhibitions.; Art -- Study and teaching.; Cubism.; Politics in art.; Art museum directors.; Art historians.; Photoprints.
Access Restrictions
The records are open for research and contain few restricted materials.
Biographical Note
Alfred H. Barr, Jr. spent nearly his entire professional career with The Museum of Modern Art; following is brief chronology of his decades-long association with the Museum.
1902 Born January 28
1922 Graduated from Princeton University; achieved his M.A. the following year.
1923-1927 Taught courses at Vassar College, Harvard University, and Wellesley College.
1929-43 Director
1939 July (1940 June 30)-1943 October 27, Vice-President
1940 January 4, elected to Board of Trustees and named Vice President
1943 October 15, date of letter from Stephen C. Clark requesting he resign as Director of Museum
1943 October 28, named to post of "Advisory Director"
1944 named Director of Research in Painting and Sculpture
1944 October 19, at this Board meeting accepted appointment to the Chair of Modern Painting and Sculpture which was created at Board of Trustee meeting on May 11, 1944
1946 September 12-1949 October 13 Coordination Committee
1946 briefly, Executive [Committee?]
1947 February-1967 June 30, appointed Director of Museum Collections; as Director, an ex-officio member of Acquisitions Committee
1947 October on, Committee on the Museum Collections
1967 June 30, elected Counsellor to the Trustees
1968 June 13, resigned as Trustee
ca. 1970s Elected Honorary Trustee for life
1981 Died August 15
Scope and Content Note
The Alfred H. Barr, Jr. Papers are composed of files kept during Barr's tenure at the Museum of Modern Art, including personal and professional correspondence with museum officials, curators, writers, historians, critics, art associations, foundations, magazines, artists, and collectors such as John Canaday, Stanton Catlin, Camilla Gray, Ren d'Harnoncourt, John Hightower, Roland Penrose, and James Thrall Soby. Office files cover staff, exhibitions, publications and collections of MoMA, and abstract art, cubism and futurism (some related to Barr's book Cubism and Abstract Art, 1936.) There are files present on the Foundation for Arts, Religion and Culture (ARC), Barr's travels, lectures, speeches, exhibitions, publications, political controversies, and artists and collections in the U.S.S.R.; writings, including travel notebooks regarding his trip to Russia, 1959, visits with Pablo Picasso, 1956, and Henri Matisse, 1952; exhibition catalogs, clippings and printed material; and photographs.
Also included are materials collected by Margaret Scolari Barr, including Alfred's obituaries,A Memorial Tribute, 1981, an invitation and guest list to the memorial service, and condolence letters; and photocopies of autograph letters, ca. 1920s-1970s, from the Barr collection sold to Arthur A. Cohen in 1975.
Arrangement
The Papers are organized into eighteen series:
Series 1: Correspondence
Series 1b: Barr Biographical: Honors and Awards
Series 1c: Correspondence, Resor, Mrs. Stanley B.
Series 2: Tributes and Condolences 1981, 1983
Series 2a: Tributes and Condolences 1962, 1972, and undated
Series 3: Abstract Art, Cubism, and Futurism
Series 3a: Barr/Feininger Material
Series 4: Foundation for Arts, Religion and Culture (ARC)
Series 5: Lectures, Speeches/Talks and Eulogies
Series 6: Exhibitions/Publications
Series 7: Political Controversy
Series 8: Soviet Matters
Series 9: Barr Writings
Series 9a: Chronicles
Series 10: Personal/Desk
Series 11: Matisse 1946-1975
Series 11a: Matisse Addenda
Series 12: Barr Picasso Papers
Series 12a: Barr Picasso Papers: Addenda and Oversize
Series 13: Russian Material
Series 14: Harvard: Board of Overseers
Series 15: Family Letters and Early Education
Series 16: Painting and Sculpture in The Museum of Modern Art, 1977
Series 17: Removed Material; Formally 3g and 3h
Series 18: Alfred H. Barr, Jr. / Nelson A. Rockefeller Papers
Additional Descriptive Data
Explanation of Abbreviations
ALS is an Autographed Letter Signed.
TLS is a Typed Letter Signed.
TL stands for Typed Letter.
MoMA is The Museum of Modern Art.
n.d. stands for no date.
re: stands for regarding.
AHB is Alfred H. Barr, Jr.
MSB is Margaret Scolari Barr
JTS is James Thrall Soby
SCC Stephen C. Clark
ACG is A. Conger Goodyear
PJS is Paul J. Sachs
AAR is Abby Aldrich Rockefeller
PJ is Philip Johnson
NAR is Nelson A. Rockefeller
RDH is Ren d'Harnoncourt
Related Collections at MoMA and Elsewhere
Because of Barr's unique and paramount position in the museum's history, materials concerning his activities can be found in numerous additional collections. Please see an archivist with specific questions.
The Archives of American Art possess not only microfilm of the Barr papers, but also major related collections.
Container List
- Series 1: Correspondence
  Inventory reflects order of Correspondence as it was microfilmed. The name of the correspondent(s) is indicated in parenthesis when item is alphabetized under the name of an Institution. In some instances, the location and/or function of an organization is indicated in parentheses if it is no longer in existence or is not well known. From time to time correspondence between individuals other than AHB are in the papers. In those instances, the name of the author is placed in brackets next to the name of the recipient. Titles (Dr., Prof., Director...) have been eliminated; nicknames are indicated in parentheses, e.g. John E. Abbot used the nickname ("Dick"). Microfilm reel and frame are indicated as [mf roll#:frame#] in the first line of each folder description.
  - Katherine Dreier/Societé Anonyme, 1927; Yale items added to this (Box 1, Folder 1.1 mf 2164:41)
  - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, 1929-1932; Kelly, Anna L. Blackburn, Alan R. (Box 1, Folder 1.2 mf 2164:46)
  - Alfred H. Barr, Jr. tax returns, 1929; Not filmed (Box 1, Folder 1.2a)
  - A-L, 1930-1931; Abbott, Jere Brummer, Joseph Albin, Kathryn Atland, Daniel F. E. Weyhe Brownell-Lamberston Galleries American Assoc. of Museums (Siple, Walter H.) Amster and Ruthardt (Gall., Berlin) The Arts(Watson, Forbes; Robb, William) Art Center (NY; Levy, Florence N.) The Art Workshop (Educ Ctr, NY; Leslie, Mabel) Bakeless, John Baltimore Society of Independent Artists (Boas, Gregory) Barr, Alfred H., Sr. Barr, Alfred H., Jr. Barr, Andrew Abbott, Jere Stattliche Gemäldegalerie (Dresden; H. Posse) Schleswig-Holsteinischer Kunstverein Binsse, Harry Lorin Bryan, Mrs. Wilhelmus B. Burchfield, Charles Chase, George H. Children's Aid Society (NY; Osborn, Wm. Church) Churchill, Mary (Mrs. Henry S.) Clark, Stephen C. The Cleveland Museum of Art (Whiting, F.A.) College Art Assoc. (McMahon, Audrey [Mrs. A. Philip]; Nirdlinger, Miss) Creative Art(NY; Gutman, Walter; Levine, Mrs. M.) De Colliny, Isabella (Honorary Comm. Liaison Artistique et Litteraire) Close Up(London) Columbia University (Potter, Russell) Contemporary Arts (NY; Francis, Emily) Cook, Mildred Currier, J. Franklin Darby, Delphine Dwight, Mrs. Arthur Ede, H.S. (Jim) Eden, Sybil Einstein, Carl Joubin, Andre Harshe, Robert B. (Art Institute of Chicago) Phillips, Duncan Cone, Etta Erfurth, Hugo Demotte, Lucien Feininger, Lyonel Farnsworth Museum (Wellesley, MA; Hersey, Celia H.) The Evening News(London; Sizen, Reginald) Goodyear, A. Conger New York Herald Tribune (Van Doren, Irita) Hawes, Charles Harding, George Hamilton, Helen Hagen, Angela Hopkinson, Charles Howe, George Inman, Ondess L. Johnson, Mrs. Homer H. Hofer, Philip Keller, Martha Kiesler, Frederick W. Kirstein, Lincoln Johnson, Philip Klee, Paul Levy, Julien (E. Weyhe) Liebman, Mrs. Charles J. (Box 1, Folder 1.3 mf 2164:218)
  - M-Z, 1930-1931; MacDougal Street Playhouse (Hvidt-Bie, Katrine) McMahon, Mrs. A. Philip Mayor, A. Hyatt Mazaraki, Nico Morey, Charles Rufus Memorandum (2 sheets) Re: Exh. on Amer. Art, Dec. 1930 Princeton University (Baker, H. Drewry) Sachs, Maurice Osborne, Frank Pauli, Gustav Read, Helen Appleton Neago, Peter The Renaissance Society (Schütze, Mrs. Martin) Rindge, Agnes Rogers, Mrs. Rainey Rowley, George Russell, Mrs. Charles H. Sachs, Maurice (Demotte Inc.) Sachs, Paul The Saturday Review(Canby, Henry S.) School of Modern Architecture (Kocher, A. Lawrence) Schütze, Mrs. Martin (The Renaissance Society) Simon and Schuster Swroluchowska, Dorria Spahr, Mrs. Charles B. Stern, Louis E. Alkazin, Alice The Symposium(A NY Critical Review; Burnham, James) Taylor, Francis Thomson, Randall Thonet Brothers, Inc. The Town Hall Club (Brackett, A.S.) Uzielli, Mario (Frankfurt) Butow, Herr H. Vaughan, Malcolm Wadsworth Atheneum (receipt) Waite, Louise Wallace, Mrs. William K. Walls, Franklin Jasper Warburg, Edward Warren, Constance von Weber, Roland Roerich Society of NY List of Wellesley slides Wellesley College Avery, Myrtilla VanVechten Brown, Alice Moore, Alice Hersey, Celia Wellesley College Literary Review(telegram) Weyhe, E. Whidden, Mrs. Ethel Jones Women's City Club of NY (Dreier, Ethel E.) Exerpts from exam papers (Box 1, Folder 1.4 mf 2164:450)
  - A-K, 1932; Klein, Jerome (Columbia University) Sachs, Paul J. (salary table for Amer. Assoc. of Museums) AHB Appendix notes on MoMA Personnel Malette, Alice Blackburn, Alan Atland, Daniel F. Brownell, Blanche (Brownell-Lambertson Galleries, Inc.) Blackburn, Alan Sachs, Paul The American School and University(Yearbook; Clark, Anna H.) Abbott, Jere The Arts(Robb, William) Assoc. of Art Museum Directors (Burroughs, Clyde) Bannier, Jean Beuchner, Robert Blackburn, Alan Brentano's (NY Bookseller) Brewer, Joseph (Brewer, Warren & Putnam Inc.) Cahill, Holger Cashman, Sol H. (Cashman Laudry Corp.) Century Club Exh. (NY) Breck, Joseph (The Metropolitan Museum of Art) Chicago (Palmer, Potter; Art Institute) Coussinot, Elizabeth Creative Art(Glassgold, Adolph) Barr, Margaret Cunningham, John Davis, T.K. Davis, James E. Duveen Bros. Boggis, B. Eddy, Katherine Willard (The Riverside Church) Einstein, Sergi M. (American Russian Institute; Clark, Elizabeth; Counts, George) Fitzmaurice, May Gellert, Mr. (by AHB, never sent) Goodrich, Lloyd Goodyear, A. Conger Hagen, Angela Hamilton, Helen Henderson, Yandell (Yale University) Hayman, Mr. & Mrs. David Kahn, Ely Jacques Kips Bay Boys Club (Aldridge, Chester) Kates, George Kirstein, Lincoln (Hound & Horn) Klein, Jerome (Box 1, Folder 1.5 mf 2164:605)
  - L-Z, 1932; Lemann, Bernard Institute of Int'l Education Lewis, Elizabeth Ray Lewisohn, Samuel A. McKay, Frank J. Marvel, Josiah P. (Springfield Museum of Art) Mazaraki, Nico Meigs, Hester Morey, Charles Rufus (Princeton University) Heckscher, August Morgan, William F. (Navy & Marine Memorial) Mummery(Baum, Herman) Nast, Cond Nat'l Alliance of Art and Industry (Art Center) Levy, Florence N. Bement, Alon The News Review(Strunsky, Frances) Nyhuis, Mr. & Mrs. H.J. O'Callaghan, May Porter, Vernon Carroll (The Artists' Aid Committee) Richardson, Leslie Rusk, William (Wells College) Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich Kelly, Anna The Saturday Review(Canby, Henry S.) Sargeant, Genève R. Schütze, Mrs. Martin Schapiro, Meyer (Columbia University) Shelter(Levinson, Maxwell) Simons, G.J.M. Smith, Baldwin (Princeton University) Smith College (Neilson, W.A.) Sterne, Katharine G. (The New York Times) Sullivan, Mary Sullivan, Cornelius J. The Survey Graphic(Wilson, Mrs. Andrew W.) Sweeney, James Johnson The Symposium (Trowbridge, L.H.) The Daily Tar Heel(UNC Chapel Hill newspaper; Daniel, Clifton; Dungan, J.E.) T-Square(Levinson, Maxwell) United Press Assoc. (Johnson, Earl J.) Vassar College (Flanagan, Hallie) Rindge, Agnes (Vassar College) The Viking Press (Oppenheimer, George S.) Wellesley College (Avery, Myrtilla) Whitney Museum (Glassgold, C. Adolph) Wiener (Int'l Art & Advertising Service; Mallette, Alice) The Yale Review (Box 1, Folder 1.6 mf 2164:760)
  - A-L, 1933; Abbott, Jere The American Assoc. of Museums (Coleman, Laurence Vail) The American Magazine of Art(Whiting, Mrs. F.A.) The Artists' Aid Committee (Porter, Vernon Carroll) Art Center (Bement, Alon; Nat'l Alliance of Art & Industry) Austin, A. Everett Avery, Myrtilla (Wellesley College) Barr, Andrew Barry, Iris Belling, Rudolf Bier, Justus Bloomingdale, Samuel J. Blume, Mrs. Peter Bryan, William Burr, Marion Calder, Alexander ("Sandy") Carnegie Institute (Saint-Gaudens, Homer) Chicago (Palmer, Potter; Art Institute) College Art Assoc. Columbia University (Potter, Russell) The Community Church (Nadles, Hanna) Courtauld, Samuel Creative Art(Blossom, F.A.) Crowninshield, Frank Experimental Cinema Davis, James Courter, Al Fansler, Roberta M. Force, Juliana (Whitney Museum) Ford, J.D.M. (Harvard University) The Forum(Jones, Lombard C.) Blackburn, Alan [Jones, Lombard, C.] Gallatin, A.E. (Gallery of Living Art) Goodyear, A. Conger The Group Theatre (Crawford, Cheryl) Kuhn, Charles Howe, George Board of Directors of the Philadelphia Award Levinson, Maxwell (Shelter) The Philadelphia Award [Speiser, Maurice] Stokowski, Leopold The Philadelphia Award [Levinson, Maxwell;Shelter] Kansas City, Mo (William Rockhill Nelson Trust) Kates, George M. (College of Chinese Studies; Peking) Kellner, Sydney Kimball, Fiske (Penn. Museum of Art) King, Edward S. Kirstein, Lincoln (Hound & Horn) Kuhn, Charles (Fogg Art Museum) Knoblaugh, Marion Latham, LeRoy Levy, Julien Leyda, Jay (King, Carol; Shorr, Brodsky & King) (Box 1, Folder 1.7 mf 2164:906)
  - M-Z, 1933; McAndrew, John (Amer. Academy in Rome) McMahon, Philip and Audrey The Nation(Whiting, Caroline; Blackburn, Alan) The New Republic(Bliven, Bruce; Babtiste, Elizabeth; Brown, Slater; Blackburn, Alan) Liebeman, Mrs. Charles J. NYU (Bossange, E.R.) The North American Review Paine, Frances Flynn (The Cosmopolitan Club) Phi Beta Kappa Assoc. Princeton (Silber, Gordon) Fawcett, Barbara Read, Helen Appleton Rehn, Frank K.M. Rollins, F.S. Review of Reviews and World's Work(Blackburn, Alan) Shaw, Mrs. Roger Rich, Daniel Catton (Art Inst. of Chicago) Riefstahl, Rudolf M. Crowninshield, Frank Nelligan, J.J. Paul, D'Arcy Riefstahl, Rudolf M. (College Art Assoc.) Safe Deposit & Trust Co. Paul, D'Arcy Riefstahl, Rudolf M. Morey, Charles Rufus Paul, D'Arcy Robinson, Celia Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich Kelly, Anna Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rogers, John William Rorimer, James (The Metropolitan Museum of Art) Cook, Walter W.S. [Rorimer, James] Rosenberg, Paul Sachs, Paul J. Boothby, Ruth E. Scribner's Magazine Senior, E. (student) Sheppard, Jeanie (Mrs. John E.) Sompaynac, Irma de B. Sotheby & Co. Spring (Marvel, Josiah P.) Sullivan, Mary Sweeney, James J. Syracuse Museum of Fine Arts (Olmstead, Anna) Moore, Edward T. Thwaites, John A. Toll, N. (Kondakov Institute) Van de Woestyne, Helen M. Vassar (Chatterton, C.K.) Flanagan, Hallie Warburg, Edward M.M. Tyson, Levering List of suggestions for radio lecture series (Milligan, Mrs. Harold V.) Whitney Museum (Force, Juliana) Glassgold, Adolf Whitney, Mr. & Mrs. John Hay Willisch, Mariane Willoughby, Harold R. Wilson, Susanna (Box 1, Folder 1.8 mf 2164:1264)
  - Europe and Greensboro, Vt., 1933; Blackburn, Alan Warburg, Edward Mallette, Alice Blackburn, Alan Warburg, Edward Johnson, Philip Mallette, Alice Johnson, Philip ("Pippesco") Blackburn, Alan Barr, Margaret Johnson, Philip Goodyear, A. Conger Neumann, J.B. (New Art Circle) Blackburn, Alan Mallette, Alice Blackburn, Alan Crowninshield, Frank Mallette, Alice Blackburn, Alan Goodyear, A. Conger [Harshe, Robert B.; Clark, Stephen] Mallette, Alice Simonson, Lee Blackburn, Alan Lehmann-Haupt, Hellmut [Barry, Iris] Searle, Bertha Ashley [Blackburn, Alan] List of unusual talks given by Searle Blackburn, Alan Goodyear, A. Conger Johnson, Philip Blackburn, Alan Willisch, Mariane King, Edward S. (Kingibus) Johnson, Philip Blackburn, Alan (telegram) Mallette, Alice Johnson, Philip [Robert, L.W.; Treasury Dept., Washington, D.C.] Mallette, Alice Lewisohn, Samuel A. Blackburn, Alan Mallette, Alice Blackburn, Alan Mallette, Alice Blackburn, Alan Barry, Iris Mallette, Alice Johnson, Philip Bankers Trust Co. (cable transfer) Mallette, Alice Simonson, Miss Mallette, Alice Blackburn, Alan Mallette, Alice Lewisohn, Samuel A. Mallette, Alice Blackburn, Alan Lewisohn, Samuel A. Blackburn, Alan (telegram) Warburg, Edward and Gershwin, George (postcard not filmed) (Box 1, Folder 1.9 mf 2165:4)
  - Barr/MoMA, 1934; Ulrich, Ione Blackburn, Alan Fantl, Ernestine Barry, Iris Blackburn, Alan Fantl, Ernestine Blackburn, Alan AEM (? Mallette, Alice) Blackburn, Alan AEM (? Mallette, Alice) Cahill, Holger Courter, Elodie Ulrich, Ione (Box 1, Folder 1.10 mf 2165:163)
  - A-M, 1934; Abbott, Jere Abraham Lincoln High School (Friend, Leon) Allen, George C. The Artists and Writers Dinner Club (Sloan, John) Allen, George C. Avery, Myrtilla Avinoff, Andrey Walters Art Gallery Blume, Peter Bonney, Thrèse Canadian Nat'l Gallery Calder, Alexander Chatterby, Harry Y. Chicago (Harshe, Robert B.) Clark, Stephen C. Collier & Son Corp. (Beardsley, W.W.) Tupper, Harman Walters Art Gallery Collins, V. Lansing Cott, Perry B. Crane, Josephine Davis, William Carroll Ede, H.S. (Tate Gallery) Fansler, Roberta M. (Carnegie Foundation) Franc, Helen M. French Dinner (The French-America Society of NY) Gardner, Helen (Art Institute of Chicago) Garrett, Mrs. John W. Garrett, Robert Garthe, Otto Fansler, Roberta M. (Carnegie Foundation) Gimpel, Ren Goodyear, A. Conger Winterbotham, Joseph Juilliard School of Music (Kiesler, Frederick) Goodyear, A. Conger Washburn, Gordon (Albright Art Gallery) Grand Rapids (Creaser, Marion L.) Grosser, Maurice Hagen, Angela E. Halpert, Edith Gregor (The Downtown Gallery) Hemingway, Ernest Hound & Horn(Levine, Doris) Houston, Katherine Baker Howland, Murray Shipley (First Presbyterian Church) Jackson, Katherine Gauss (Charles Scribner's Sons) Kates, George N. Kimball, Fiske F(Pennsylvania Museum of Art) King, Edward S. ("Kingibus") Kirstein, Lincoln Kuhn, Charles L. Lane, James W. Healey, Francis C. (First Municipal Art Exhibition) Levy, Julien Lurçat, Jean McMahon, A. Philip Marvel, Josiah P. Miller, Dorothy Morey, Charles Rufus (Box 1, Folder 1.11 mf 2165:21)
  - N-Z, 1934; Nadejena-Krinkin, Lydia Nat'l Child Labor Committee (Dinwiddie, Courtnenay) Niles, Edward The Northfield Schools Offner, Richard Panofsky, Erwin ("Pan") Park, Edwin Avery ("Billy") Pleasants, Freddy Porter, Mrs. Kingsley A. Princeton Nat'l Alumni Assoc. Resor, Mrs. Stanley (Foote, Natalie, J. Walter Thompson Co.) Reznikoff, Misha Rowan, Edward B. (Treasury Dept., Washington) Rich, Daniel Catton Rindge, Agnes Rockefeller, Mr. & Mrs. Nelson A. Pratt, Mrs. Harold Irving Rosenberg, James N. Ross, Cary Rowley, George Rusk, William S. Sachs, Paul Sarah Lawrence College (Warren, Constance) Sarfatti, Margherita G. The School Art League of NYC (La Farge, C. Grant) Rockefeller, Mrs. Nelson Aldrich Searle, Bertha Sloane, Joseph C. Smith College Stapleton, Laurence Stevenson, William E. Stewart, Andrew W. Stohlman, Freddy Sunami, Soichi Swan, Nathalie Sweeney, James J. Taylor, Francis H. (Worcester Art Museum) Thomson, Virgil The NY Times Literary Supplement Van Hook, Katrina Vassar College (Challerton, C.K.) Lincoln, Marion Vassar Coop. Bookshop Wald, Albert (NY State Senate) Wehle, Harry B. (The Metropolitan Museum of Art) Whitney, John Hay Wiener, Paul & Alma Willoughby, Harold R. (Box 1, Folder 1.12 mf 2165:440)
  - Association of Museum Directors, 1935-1937; Mallette, Alice MacLean, J. Arthur (Toledo Museum of Art) City Art Museum of St. Louis Rogers, Meyric R. LaBeaume, Louis MacLean, J. Arthur LaBeaume, Louis (Marceau, Henri) Rogers, Meyric R. (City Art Museum, MO) MacLean, J. Arthur LaBeaume, Louis Minnigerode, C. Powell MacLean, J. Arthur Harshe, Robert B. MacLean, J. Arthur Harshe, Robert B. Arthur, MacLean, J. Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich Kelly, Anna Rowe, L. Earle MacLean, J. Arthur Scholle, Hardinge MacLean, J. Arthur Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich Goodyear, A. Conger Packard, Artemas Preliminary Program for 1936 Mtg. of Assoc. of Art Museum Directors Kelly, Anna [Mabry, Thomas Dabney, Jr.] MacLean, J. Arthur (Toledo Museum of Art) Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich MacLean, J. Arthur [Youtz, Philip N.] Montgomery, Virginia (The Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences) Memorandum for NY Committee of the Assoc. of Art Museum Directors MacLean, J. Arthur Worcester Art Museum (Taylor, Francis Henry) (Box 1, Folder 1.13 mf 2165:626)
  - A-L, 1935; The MoMA Film Library Corp. Abbott, John E. ("Dick") Barry, Iris Onondaga? Abbott, Jere The American Mercury(Ferman, J.W.) Norman, Dorothy S. Art Front(Baron, H.S.) Barr, Margaret Jard, Irène (Princeton University) Fantl, Ernestine M. Barry, Iris Bauer, E. Beddington, Jack Benson, E.M. Blackburn, Alan (telegram) Bliss, Robert Woods (telegram) Bossange, E.R. Blume, Peter Breckinridge, Mrs. Henry (City of NY Municipal Art Committee) Colby, Elinor Coan, Constance Rogers Columbia University (Dinsmoor, W.B.) Cone, Etta The Cosmopolitan Club (Palmer, Charleton H.) Ede, H.S. Jim? Eisenhart, L.F. Fantl, Ernestine Finch School Flechtheim, Alfred Floyd, William & Louis Adams Forbes, Edward W. Roger Fry Memorial Fund Martin, Alec Heather, E.N. Gardner, Helen (Art Institute of Chicago) German Consul General in NY Goeller, Charles L. Goodyear, A. Conger Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich Halpert, Edith G. (The Downtown Gallery) Hall, Clifton Hepburn, Mrs. Barton Hitchcock, Henry-Russell Jouvène, Alex Hofer, Philip (The Pierpont Morgan Library) Johnson, Philip Junior League (Beach, Josephine) Klein, Jerome Chase, George Davis Kennedy, Clarence (Smith College) Lange, Hans (Philharmonic Chamber Orchestra) Little Brown & Co. (Blanchard, Charles B.) Lynes, George Platt (Box 1, Folder 1.14 mf 2165:725)